If I check this box in the app then it'll add the whipped cream
如果我点击应用里的复选框 那么它将
topping to our coffee.
添加生奶到咖啡中
&gt;&gt; That will make the coffee more delicious.
那将使咖啡变得更加美味
&gt;&gt; Yeah. &gt;&gt; And perhaps more expensive.
- 是啊 - 也可能更贵
&gt;&gt; True.
真的
Eventually we're going to have to learn how to create an order summary and
最后我们要学习怎样创建一个订单汇总
then send it off.
然后把它发出去
&gt;&gt; Oh, so when we send the order summary, that's when we get the coffee.
当我们发送订单汇总的时候 那是我们得到咖啡的时候
Right? &gt;&gt; Yeah.
— 真的？ — 对
&gt;&gt; That's good.
这很好
&gt;&gt; The problem is we don't exactly know if the box is checked or
问题是我们不确切地知道这个复选框是否被选中
not &gt;&gt; Wait, you just checked the box.
等一下 你只是选中复选框
I know you checked the box.
我知道你已经选中复选框了
&gt;&gt; Well it's easy for a human to see, but it's hard for the phone to see.
它对于人来说是很容易的看到的 但是对于手机来说很难
&gt;&gt; Who you calling a human?
你是说我是个人？
&gt;&gt; Anyways, when you add the CheckBox to your app,
无论如何 当你添加 CheckBox 到你的应用时
then it's actually creating a Java object.
它实际上是创建了一个 Java 对象
[SOUND] Like this.
像这个
&gt;&gt; How many of these boxes are out there?
这里有多少盒子？
&gt;&gt; Many, because in fact, inside the CheckBox object we have a variable.
很多 因为事实上 CheckBox 对象内有一个变量
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好
&gt;&gt; A Boolean variable.
一个 boolean (布尔) 变量
&gt;&gt; Boolean?
boolean？
Haven't heard that word before.
之前没有听过这个单词
&gt;&gt; Well a Boolean just means that there's two states here.
boolean 只是意味着这有两个状态
&gt;&gt; Like New York and California?
像纽约和加利福尼亚州？
&gt;&gt; No. It's more like a light switch.
不是 它更像一个电灯开关
[SOUND] &gt;&gt; Damn it.
该死的
How do you do this?
你怎么做这个
Anyways.
无论如何
So you're saying when we created a CheckBox, we had a Java object.
所以你说当我们创建一个 CheckBox 的时候我们有一个 Java 对象
Inside of that we have a variable of type Boolean.
在里面我们有一个 boolean 类型的变量
&gt;&gt; Right.
对
&gt;&gt; And the type of that variable is either on or off.
变量的类型是开或者关
&gt;&gt; The value of it is yeah, on or off.
它的值是开或者关
&gt;&gt; Okay, so I can turn the value from on to off.
好 我可以转换值从开到关
&gt;&gt; I can't see anything.
我看不到任何东西了
Can you turn it back on?
你能把它转换成开吗？
We're not done yet.
我们还没有讲完
&gt;&gt; Oh, okay. &gt;&gt; Okay, so
- 好 - 好
Boolean can have two states, true or false.
所以 boolean 能够有两个状态 true 或者 false
And that represents the checked state of this CheckBox.
这代表着这个复选框的选中状态
&gt;&gt; Whoa, that's a lot of checks in that statement.
哇哦 这里的限制条件好多
Let's just back up.
我们从头开始
I'm going to summarize.
我要去总结
Tell me if I got this wrong.
如果我说错了就告诉我
So when we create the CheckBox we created this Java object.
所以当我创建 CheckBox 时 我们就创建了这个 Java 对象
Inside of that Java object we have a variable.
在 Java 对象里我们有一个变量
Its type happens to be Boolean, and that type of variable can hold two values,
它的类型是 Boolean 类型 该类型的变量可以有两个值
either on or off, one or zero, true or false.
开或者关 1或0 真或假
&gt;&gt; Exactly.
对的
&gt;&gt; Okay. So let's play with the Boolean.
让我们看一下 Boolean 变量
[SOUND] &gt;&gt; Okay.
好
it's time to take that away from you.
是时候将它远离你了
[LAUGH] Let's look at what the documentation
让我们看一下哪些文档
says about Booleans.
说了关于 boolean 的东西
I'm going to Google search for Java data type.
我将用 Google 搜索 java data type
That's because Boolean is one of the primitive data types in Java.
那是因为 boolean 是 Java 里的原始数据之一
Primitive, meaning basic data types.
Primitive 意思是基本数据类型
I'm going to scroll through this list of primitive
我将滚动这个原始数据类型列表
data types until I find Boolean.
直到我找到 boolean
And here it is.
它在这里
It says the Boolean data type only has two possible values, true and false.
它说 boolean 数据类型值有两个可能值 true 或 false
It's used for simple flags that track true and false conditions.
它被用作跟踪真假条件的简单标志
Then it says that a Boolean takes up one bit of information.
然后它说一个 boolean 占有1位的信息
This is about how much space it takes up on a computer.
这是关于它占有计算机的空间大小
Anyways, the important part is that a Boolean has two possible values.
反正 重要的部分是 boolean 有两个可能的值
You might think that true and
你可能会认为
false are actually string values because they're text, but
true 和 false 是字符串 因为它们是文本
actually, they're not in double quotations, so they're not strings.
但是实际上 它们没有双引号 所以不是字符串
They're actually fixed literal values.
它们是固定的文字值
Do you remember how fixed literal values are zero and one or
你还记得怎样固定文字值是0和1
specific strings like hello or today?
或者像 hello 或 today 这样特定的字符串
That means that when you create a Boolean variable you can set it to one
那意味着当你创建一个 boolean 变量时 你可以将它设为
of these two values.
两个值之一
Going back to our box analogy, if we have a variable called isChecked and
返回到我们的盒子分析 如果有一个叫 isChecked 的变量
it stores information on whether a CheckBox is checked or not,
它储存 CheckBox 是否被选中的信息
then inside this Boolean variable we can store the value true.
然后在这个 boolean变量里面 可以存储值 true
Then we can interpret this as the CheckBox being checked.
我们可以把这点解释为复选框被选中
Or we can store the value false inside this variable.
或者我们可以在这个变量里储存值 false
Then we could interpret this as the CheckBox not being checked.
意味着复选框没有被选中
A Boolean is great for having two possible states.
一个 boolean 有两个可能状态是很好的
Then it's up to you as a developer to interpret what true and false maps to.
是 true 还是 false 全部由你来决定
If you need more than two possible states then you can't use a Boolean.
如果你需要超过两种可能状态 那么你不能使用 boolean
You need to use something else like a string or an integer.
你需要使用像一个 String 或 int 的其它类型
Declaring a Boolean variable is very similar to declaring an int.
声明 boolean 变量和声明 int 类型是非常相似的
It's not as complicated as creating an object variable.
它没有创建一个对象变量复杂
It follows the format of Boolean hasWhippedCream = true.
它遵循 Boolean hasWhippedCream = true 的格式
We have the data type, which is Boolean, followed by the variable name, which
我们有数据类型 boolean 接着是变量名
can be anything we want, and then the initial value which is true or false.
它可以是你想的任何名 然后是初始值是 true 或 false
Here are a couple of other examples.
这里有几个其他的例子
This is where I set the same Boolean to be false.
这个我设置相同的 boolean为 false
And here's a different Boolean called isRegistered,
这里有一个不同的 boolean 变量叫 isRegistered
and I just initialize that to false.
我只是初始化它为 false
For example, this variable could represent whether a user using our app
例如 这个变量可能代表实际上使用我们应用的用户
actually has a registered account with us.
是否注册了账户
Here's another example.
这另一个例子
Boolean isOrderForPickup = true.
Boolean isOrderForPickup = true；
This variable could represent whether someone putting in an order for
这个变量可以用来表示客户所点的咖啡
some coffee wants to pick it up at the store or have it delivered.
是在店里享用 还是打包带走
While our app doesn't support these features, you can imagine how using
虽然我们的应用不支持这些功能 你可以想象
Booleans could be useful because these things have two possible states.
怎样使用 boolean 是有用的 因为这些东西有两个可能的状态
Also notice the way I named these variables.
还要注意到我命名这些变量的方式
A Boolean variable name has to follow the same conventions as other
boolean 变量名必须遵循相同的约定
variable names.
就像其他变量名一样
However, it's common to start with something like has something or
然而 常见的是以 has 或 is
is something.
开始
When you see names with has or is, it's likely a Boolean but not always.
当你看到有 has 或 is 的名字 它很可能是 boolean 类型的 但是并非总是如此
What I'm about to show you is a little more advanced and optional.
接下来介绍的有点超前所以不要求你现在掌握
So if you're interested you can follow along.
如果你感兴趣可以跟着做
This is the documentation page for the CheckBox class.
这是 CheckBox 类的文档页
I'm going to click on view source to look at the source code for
我将点击 view source 来查看 CheckBox 类的
the CheckBox class.
源代码
This code is saved in the CheckBox.java file.
这个代码保存在 CheckBox.java 文件里
I want to show you that there's a Boolean variable inside of this
我想要显示给你这个 boolean变量
CheckBox class.
在这个 CheckBox 类里的
But I don't see it here, so let's check the super class.
在这里看不到它 所以我们选中父类
If this value is true then the CheckBox is checked.
如果这个值是 true 那么 CheckBox 被选中
If it's false then the box is not checked.
如果它是 false 那么 CheckBox 没有被选中
You'll notice that this name doesn't contain the word has or is, but
你会注意到这个名字不包含单词 has 或 is
if you go down here you'll see that the other Boolean variables
但是如果你向下看这里 你会看到另一个 boolean 变量
do have the word has in it.
它有单词 has
It's all a matter of preference for the developer.
这都是倾向于开发人员的问题
In this case, it's probably pretty clear that this is a Boolean for
在这种情况下 它可能是非常清楚的它是一个 boolean变量
the checked state.
对于选中状态
And while this Boolean is not found directly in the CheckBox.java file,
虽然这个 boolean 变量没有在 CheckBox.java 文件被直接发现
since we're inheriting from the CompoundButton class,
因为我们是从 CompoundButton 类继承来的
we get this checked Boolean for free.
这种选中状态还是很容易就能得到的
In general, looking at the source code for
一般来说 看 Android 类的源代码
the Android classes isn't required at all.
并不是必需的
To develop Android apps,
为了开发 Android 应用
all you need to know is how to look at the documentation pages.
你需要知道的怎样看文档页
Okay, so in this video we learned about how Booleans can store
好了 所以这个视频我们学习关于 boolean变量怎样储存
a value of true or false.
true 或者 false 值
In this quiz, practice creating a Boolean variable and
在这个测验里 练习创建一个 boolean 变量
updating it by typing out the lines of code in the boxes provided.
通过输入框里的代码来进行更新
Type this line exactly in here and same for the other boxes.
输如这行代码到这 同样其他行的代码输入到其他的框里
Then I want you to think about other good use cases for
然后我希望你考虑一下其他好的例子
storing information in a Boolean.
对于在一个 boolean 变量里储存信息
Think about what has two possible states.
想想什么有两种状态
Do you ever use alarm clock on your phone to wake up?
你曾经使用过手机闹钟早起么？
Well chances are that when you turn your alarm on or
当你开关闹钟的时候
off, that that's actually getting stored as a Boolean variable.
会有一个 boolean 变量储存信息
Another possible Boolean variable is whether you want to
另一个可能用到的 boolean变量是你是否想要
repeat an alarm or not.
重复闹钟
In the Gmail app, if I really want to star this special message that I got
在 Gmail 应用里 如果我想收藏这个2011年里 Google 团队发给我的邮件
from the Gmail team in 2011, then I can star it, or I can unstar it.
我可以添加星标或者取消星标
Since this has two states, it could be stored as a Boolean variable.
因为这有两种状态 它可以作为 boolean 变量被储存
A possible Boolean variable name for that could be isStarred.
对于这个可能的布尔变量名是 isStarred
You could also use a Boolean variable to keep track of whether an email
你也可以使用一个布尔变量跟踪一个邮件
is read or not.
是否被阅读
This email is unread, whereas this email is already read.
这个邮件未读 而这个邮件现在是已读
Speaking of YouTube let's go to the YouTube app.
谈到 YouTube 我们到 YouTube 的应用里看一看
In the YouTube app, when it displays a list of videos,
在 YouTube 的应用里 显示视频列表时
if I've already watched it, then it shows this little text box here
如果我们看过它 这里会显示这个小的文本框
that says watched in the top left corner of the thumbnail image.
写着 watched 在缩略图图像的左上角
The fact that I've watched or
我们看过或
not watched the video could also be stored as a Boolean variable.
没有看过视频的事实也可能作为一个 boolean 变量存储
I just showed you some use cases for Booleans, so
我只是给你据一些 boolean 变量的例子
try to come up with your own here.
所以试着在这里写出自己的例子
You can browse existing Android apps for some ideas.
你可以浏览现有的 Android 应用看看有没有类似的例子